在这个视频中，我们将介绍神经网络和它的架构，以及如何将额外信息融入其中。
In this video, we'll go over the neural network, the architecture of it, and how we can incorporate additional information into it.
我们用于扩散模型的神经网络架构是一个UNet。
So the neural network architecture that we use for diffusion models is a UNet.
关于UNet最重要的是，
And the most important thing that you need to know about a UNet is that
它将图像作为输入，输出与图像大小相同的预测噪声。
it is taking as input this image and it's producing as output something of the same size as that image, but here it is that predicted noise.
UNet已经存在很长时间了，自2015年以来，它首次被用于图像分割。
UNets have been around for a very long time, since 2015, and it was first used for image segmentation.
它最初被用来将一张图片中的行人或汽车分割出来，
It was first used to take an image and actually segment it into either a pedestrian or a car,
因此在自动驾驶汽车研究中得到了广泛应用。
so it's used a lot in self-driving car research.
但UNet的特殊之处在于其输入和输出大小相同。
But what's special about UNets is just that its input and outputs are the same size.
它首先将这个输入的信息嵌入，
And what it does is it first embeds information about this input,
通过许多卷积层将其降采样到一个压缩了所有信息的嵌入中，
so it downsamples with a lot of convolutional layers into an embedding that compresses all that information into a small amount of space,
然后用相同数量的上采样块将输出返回到任务中。
and then it upsamples with the same number of upsampling blocks into the output back out for its task.
在这个例子中，它的任务就是预测应用到这个图片上的噪音。
And in this case, that task is to predict the noise that was applied to this image.
如果你想深入了解，我们可以一起来看看，
And if you want to look a little bit deeper, which we'll do together,
这些命名块在代码中也用相同的名称显示。
is that each of these named blocks here are also shown in the code with the same names.
这个预测的噪声与原始输入图像的尺寸相同，16x16x3。
And this predicted noise is the same dimension, 16,16 by 3, of the original input image.
UNet的另一个优点是它可以接收额外的信息。
What's also great about this UNet is that it can take in additional information.
所以它压缩了图像以了解发生了什么，但也可以接收更多信息。
So it's compressed that image to understand what's going on, but it can also take in more information.
那么我们想要包括拿些信息呢？
And so what information do we want to include?
对于这些模型来说，一个非常重要的信息就是时间嵌入。
Well, one thing that's really important for these models is the time embedding.
这是一种告诉模型时间步长的嵌入，
And so this is an embedding that kind of tells the model what the time step is,
因此我们需要某种级别的噪音。
and therefore what kind of noise level we need.
对于这个时间嵌入，你需要做的就是将它嵌入到一个向量中，
And all you have to do for this time embedding is you embed it into some kind of vector,
然后将其添加到这些上采样块中。
and you can add it into these upsampling blocks.
另一个有用的信息是上下文嵌入。
Another piece of information that could be useful is a context embedding.
我们稍后会更深入地讨论这个，但上下文嵌入的作用就是帮助你控制模型生成的内容。
We'll do more of this later, but all that context embedding does is it helps you control what the model generates.
例如，一个文本描述，你想让它生成的是Bob，或者某种因子，比如需要是某种颜色。
For example, a text description, like you really want it to be Bob, or some kind of factor like it needs to be a certain color.
稍后我们会再讨论这个问题。
We'll discuss this a bit more later.
对于这个上下文嵌入，你只需要将它乘进去就可以了。
And for that context embedding, you can just multiply it in.
很好！
Great.
那么这在代码中是什么样子的呢？
So what does that look like in code?
这里你可以看到一个上下文嵌入。
Here you can see a context embedding.
这只是其中之一。
This is just one of them.
然后在这里你可以看到时间嵌入。
And then here you see the time embedding.
在上采样模块中，你需要做的就是像图示中那样，
And in the upsampling block, all you have to do again, just like in this diagram,
把上下文嵌入乘以上采样块，然后加上时间嵌入。
you multiply the context embedding with the upsampling block, and you add the time embedding.
很好！
Cool.
那么现在，在 Notebook 的模型前向传递中，这就是运行模型，
So now in the notebook, in the forward pass of the model, so this is running the model,
你可以看到一些这样的下采样块，然后也有这些上采样块。
you can see some of these down, down, down blocks, and then also these up, up, up blocks here.
再次强调，这里是你的上下文和时间嵌入。
And again, here are your context and time embeddings.
我们在这里为每一个上采样块都设置了两个。
We have two of them here for each of those up blocks.
这些上采样和下采样块是如何定义的，是在UNet的初始化部分定义的。
And how these down and up blocks are defined is up here in initialization for the UNet.
所以对于下采样，这就是一个UNet下采样的样子。
And so for the down, this is what a UNet down looks like.
如果你想详细了解的话我们实际上在我们的辅助函数中也有这个。
And we actually do have that in our helper functions if you want to look at them in greater detail.
但它们就是卷积块。
But they are just convolutional blocks.
在下一个视频中，你将学会如何训练这个神经网络。
And in the next video, you'll learn how to train this neural network.